<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>wellness &#8211; Dailytweet</title>
	<atom:link href="/category/wellness/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>/</link>
	<description></description>
	<lastBuildDate>Thu, 07 Jan 2021 11:02:34 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=5.6</generator>

<image>
	<url>/wp-content/uploads/2020/12/cropped-android-chrome-512x512-1-1-32x32.png</url>
	<title>wellness &#8211; Dailytweet</title>
	<link>/</link>
	<width>32</width>
	<height>32</height>
</image> 
	<item>
		<title>CAN WE EAT CURD AT NIGHT? – IS IT SAFE TO EAT YOGURT AT NIGHT</title>
		<link>/can-we-eat-curd-at-night-is-it-safe-to-eat-yogurt-at-night/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[adminilyes1]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 06 Jan 2021 13:06:21 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[wellness]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=688</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Curd or Yogurt is very useful for your gut, stomach, and your overall health. It contains good fats, a good amount of protein and good bacteria which are very essential for our gut. In this article, I will tell you that is it safe to eat curt at night or before going to bed? Curd [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>Curd or Yogurt is very useful for your gut, stomach, and your overall health. It contains good fats, a good amount of protein and good bacteria which are very essential for our gut. In this article, I will tell you that is it safe to eat curt at night or before going to bed?</p>



<p>Curd or Yogurt is a fermented form of milk that is made by adding live bacteria to it. According to Healthline, 245 grams of yogurt contains 8.5 grams of the whole protein.</p>



<p>Should you eat curd at night or not</p>



<p>It also contains carbs, sugar, calcium, and some very essential vitamins and minerals. So far, we can conclude that Yogurt is nutritionally excellent for our health and body. We should not miss it in our daily eatings and must use it in our daily life to get all of its benefits. You can more about Yogurt nutrition and benefits on MedicalNewsToday.</p>



<p>It is a good source of bioavailable proteins, vitamins, and calcium which can strengthen your body.</p>



<p>Without wasting any further time, let’s see if we can eat curt at night, or is it safe to eat yogurt before sleeping at night?</p>



<p>Should Not Eat If<br>Victim of Cold or Cough:<br>If you are having a cough or victim of cold flu, then you must clearly avoid having curd at night before going to bed. It is because, according to Ayurveda, eating curd at night develops mucus and in this way, flu can get harder on you. So, in this case, avoid having it at night.</p>



<p>Swelling or Inflammation:<br>You should also avoid having it at night if you have any swelling or inflammation in any of your body parts or joints. It will create more complications.</p>



<p>Suffering From Allergy or Asthma:<br>In some cases, it can cause serious complications by blocking the breathing pipe.</p>



<script async src="https://pagead2.googlesyndication.com/pagead/js/adsbygoogle.js"></script>
<ins class="adsbygoogle"
     style="display:block; text-align:center;"
     data-ad-layout="in-article"
     data-ad-format="fluid"
     data-ad-client="ca-pub-7408619455147859"
     data-ad-slot="9053070773"></ins>
<script>
     (adsbygoogle = window.adsbygoogle || []).push({});
</script>



<p>Heavy to Digest<br>Eating curd at night is heavy to digest, and it can cause some acidity in your stomach. But if you are not suffering from any cold or inflammation and you want to eat curd at night, then add some sugar or black pepper to it and then consume it. This will aid the digestion process.</p>



<p>Right Ways to Eat Curd At Night<br>You can consume curd at night in the right ways, as I have told you in the previous point that adding some sugar or black pepper to the bowl of curd can make it more digestible.</p>



<p>You can also add it to various other recipes and add to your diet in dinners.</p>



<p>Curd Rice<br>Add some curd to boiled rice and consume it. You can also add some sugar according to your taste.</p>



<p>Kadhi<br>It is a traditional recipe, it is prepared using gram flour, buttermilk and probably adding some yogurt. You can check the Kadhi Recipe here.</p>



<p>Raita<br>Raita is a mixture of yogurt and some vegetables like onion, cucumber, some spice, and salt. It is also made with mint, cumin, green chillis, salt, and yogurt. You mix ’em up and it’s ready. Want to make raita, check the recipe here.</p>



<p>Some other recipes include:</p>



<p>Lassi<br>Sweet Curd<br>etc.<br>In this way, you can consume curd at night if you want to. Also, keep in mind that don’t miss it in your daily diet and daily routine.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>HOW 3 HOME REMEDIES CAN PREVENT THE RISK OF HEART DISEASE?</title>
		<link>/how-3-home-remedies-can-prevent-the-risk-of-heart-disease/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[adminilyes1]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 06 Jan 2021 12:43:41 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[wellness]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=679</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[As we know that the risk of heart disease is so common in the people of different localities and age groups. World wide among countries like the United States and others, about 610,000 people die due to heart disease every year. This means that 1 in every 4 deaths. Heart disease is the leading reason [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>As we know that the risk of heart disease is so common in the people of different localities and age groups. World wide among countries like the United States and others, about 610,000 people die due to heart disease every year. This means that 1 in every 4 deaths. Heart disease is the leading reason for death for men and women, the most common type of heart disease is Coronary heart disease (CHD), mortality over 370,000 people per annum. Nearly 48%, 121.5 million in 2016, of all adults in the United States have some type of cardiovascular disease. The world’s leading cause of death is Heart disease. Approximately It is 15.5% of all deaths worldwide.</p>



<p>A total of 160,000 people die in the UK each year from circulatory diseases. Due to CVD, 38% of males and 37% of female deaths in the UK are caused by this disease.</p>



<p>In China, a figure of around 230 million people suffers from CVD. 931 deaths per 100,000 of the population in the country are a direct result of either stroke or CVD.</p>



<p>In Russia, the standard mortality rate due to CVD is the highest among all of the developed nations in the world, which is 57% of all deaths due to CVD, ie 1,752 heart disease-related deaths per 100,000 people.</p>



<p>Hereditary, social, and physical factors combine to create a perfect storm for cardiovascular disease deaths.</p>



<p>Your home is the best place to start!</p>



<p>Garlic</p>



<p>It is a great gift of God for human beings. Its medicinal name is Allium Sativum. Originally from central Asia, garlic grows everywhere. It is safe for domestic use and effective in treating a multitude of health problems. It fights infections of the nose, throat, bronchi and etc.</p>



<p>Mainly it reduces the cholesterol level and thinning of blood is an important characteristic. It is also valuable in diabetes. Garlic also enhances the body’s immune system. Garlic prevents the arteries from clogging and reduces the risk of plaque building or arteriosclerosis. Garlic also reduces blood pressure and improves the flow of blood in the system. Garlic contains a sulfur compound known as allicin, it is responsible for most of the health benefits. Garlic contains the most powerful antioxidant. Garlic could reduce your LDL ( bad cholesterol) by as much as 10 to 15 per cent, if you take Garlic ( 4-5 cloves chopped, crushed or chewed) with a glass of freshwater in the morning ½ an hour before breakfast on a daily basis.</p>



<p>Turmeric</p>



<p>The Golden Spice, or The Indian Saffron. It is a miracle and a wonderful product. Turmeric is a flowering plant, Curcuma longa of the ginger family, Zingiberaceae, the roots of which are used for multi-purposes.</p>



<p>Turmeric, especially its most active compound curcumin has many scientifically proven health benefits, such as the potential to prevent heart disease, Alzheimer’s and cancer diseases. It’s a potent anti-inflammatory and antioxidant and may also help improve symptoms of depression and arthritis. It has got sufficient blood-thinning properties. The purifying properties of turmeric may also lead to bleed more easily. Turmeric lowers cholesterol and blood pressure.</p>



<p>People who take blood-thinning medications, such as warfarin (Coumadin), should avoid taking turmeric in large doses.</p>



<p>Under certain conditions, clinical trials have concluded that turmeric can help to lower triglycerides and cholesterol levels. Current evidence suggests curcumin may be beneficial if you are obese, have metabolic syndrome, diabetes, or another chronic condition affecting your blood lipid profile. You always take proper consultation and advice from your family doctor or nutritionist to use any of the ingredients.</p>



<p>Oatmeal</p>



<p>Let us see the oatmeal, what it is? And how it is beneficial for the health purpose of different types and conditions. Actually oatmeal is a whole grain food and it is scientifically known as Avena Sativa. Oats, the intact and whole form of oats, take a long span of time to cook. Due to this cause, generally, people prefer rolled, crushed or steel-cut oats.</p>



<p>The most highly processed variety is Instant ( quick) oats. because they have the shortest time to cook, the texture can mushy. Oats are commonly eaten for breakfast as oatmeal, which is made by boiling oats in the water or milk. Oatmeal is often referred to as porridge. Often mixed in muffins, granola bars, cookies, and also in baked goods.</p>



<p>Oats are among the healthiest grains on earth. whole grain, which is gluten-free and great mean of vitamins, minerals, fibre, and antioxidants. It is a great source of fibre and multi-minerals.</p>



<p>conducted Studies reveals that oats and oatmeal have various health benefits. It included weight loss, lower blood glucose levels and a diminished risk of heart disease.</p>



<p>Globally the leading cause of death is Heart disease. One major risk factor is high blood cholesterol. Many studies have shown that beta-glucan fibre in oats is effective at reducing both total and LDL cholesterol levels. Beta-glucan may increase the excretion of cholesterol-rich bile, thereby reducing circulating levels of cholesterol in the blood. Oxidation of LDL( the bad cholesterol) which occurs when LDL reacts with free radicals, is another crucial step in the progression of heart disease. It produces inflammation in arteries, damages and can raise the risk of heart attacks and strokes. IN oats, antioxidants work combine with vitamin c to protect LDL oxidation.</p>



<p>The baseline is that oats may lower the risk of heart disease by reducing both total LDL cholesterol and protecting LDL cholesterol from oxidation.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>WHAT ARE THE EARLY SIGNS AND SYMPTOMS OF RHEUMATOID ARTHRITIS?</title>
		<link>/what-are-the-early-signs-and-symptoms-of-rheumatoid-arthritis/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[adminilyes1]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 06 Jan 2021 12:32:33 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[wellness]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=676</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[According to Arthritis Foundation, Rheumatoid Arthritis is an autoimmune disease in which our immune system mistakenly attacks our body joints. In this article, we will see How Rheumatoid Arthritis develops and what are the symptoms of Rheumatoid Arthritis and its early warning signs. How does RA Develop?In Rheumatoid Arthritis our body’s immune system attacks our [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>According to Arthritis Foundation, Rheumatoid Arthritis is an autoimmune disease in which our immune system mistakenly attacks our body joints. In this article, we will see How Rheumatoid Arthritis develops and what are the symptoms of Rheumatoid Arthritis and its early warning signs.</p>



<p>How does RA Develop?<br>In Rheumatoid Arthritis our body’s immune system attacks our joints and as a result, the tissues which surround the joints thickens and inflammation is created. The pain and swelling are produced around the joint.</p>



<p>In the long run, both joint bones can fuse with each other and it can result in movable joints. In moderate cases, the movement of the joint is very limited due to this disease and joints become very painful. Wikipedia explained it very well.</p>



<p>Who Develops RA?<br>It includes genetic factors like many other diseases. If any of the family members is a victim of RA then its most likely to transmit in children. RA most commonly begins within the age of 30 and 60 and in men, it occurs later in life. Some resources say that women are most likely to develop Rheumatoid Arthritis then males.</p>



<p>People with RA can have more risk of obesity or heart diseases, diabetes, and high blood pressure. Depression can also develop along with Rheumatoid Arthritis.</p>



<p>Now let’s take a look at symptoms of Rheumatoid Arthritis and its warning signs. And when you should take action.</p>



<p>1. Fatigue<br>Fatigue is a result of joint inflammation, poor sleep or reaction to medications in rheumatoid arthritis. You will feel very tired and less energy in the body.</p>



<p>It can adversely affect your relationships, work routine, mental capability and more. You may develop fatigue in the day or morning.</p>



<p>2. Joint Pain<br>When joints develop inflammation then it leads to joint pain. This is because in RA joint tissues are damaged.</p>



<p>In RA when WBCs attack our joint cells and bones, synovium gets damaged and swelling appears inside of tissue. This then stretches the tissue and capsule which surrounds the joint, this causes joint pain. In RA joint pain affect both sides of the body.</p>



<p>3. Morning Stiffness<br>Stiffness which remains for some minutes in the morning or after napping. This may last for 30 minutes or longer. This is the early symptom of arthritis and can worsen over time.</p>



<p>This can also be caused after you keep sitting for a long time or joints stay at rest. If you feel stiffness and hard to move your joints. Then it is a symptom of RA.</p>



<p>4. Joint Stiffness<br>Joint stiffness is the main symptom of RA. This can occur at any time of the day, while you are active or not. Joints become hard to move.</p>



<p>5. Swelling<br>Swelling occurs in your joints and you also feel pain due to this swelling. This makes appear your joints bigger than normal and swelling is also associated with joint warmth.</p>



<p>6. Joint Tenderness<br>In simple words, joints are painful when touched. This is because the swelling and RA irritated the nerves in the joint capsule. You can become very uncomfortable with it.</p>



<p>7. Joint Redness<br>Due to the inflammation occurs in the joints, joints become red. This is because due to swelling capillaries are widened by adjacent inflammation. You can see it normally on the affected joints.</p>



<p>8. Joint Deformity<br>When you develop chronic rheumatoid arthritis, your joints start to deform themselves. This is because of swelling and in chronic conditions bones fuse together in joints and they can grow abnormally and uncontrolled.</p>



<p>9. Limited motion<br>It limits the motion of the affected joint and you will feel difficulty and pain when you try to move your affected joint at a normal angle.</p>



<p>You will unable to move or bend your joints. Your range of motion will be affected due to pain and stiffness. A gentle exercise and yoga can help to get relief.</p>



<p>10. Both Sides of Body is Affected<br>In the case of rheumatoid arthritis joints of both sides of the body are equally affected.</p>



<p>11. Other Symptoms of RA<br>Eyes are also affected.<br>More than one joints are affected.<br>Weight loss<br>Loss of Appetite<br>Weakness<br>Fever<br>What to do If RA is Diagnosed – Treatment?<br>As soon as you observe any symptoms of RA, you must take proper tests and consult your physician. They might recommend you some blood tests, imaging scans or X-Rays scans. In addition, you can find some very useful diagnosis and treatment tips at Mayoclinic and <a rel="noreferrer noopener" target="_blank" href="http://arthritis.org/">Arthritis.org</a>.</p>



<p>Share this article as much as you can with your beloved ones and let us know your thoughts in comments below.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>10 CANCER-CAUSING FOODS YOU SHOULD STOP EATING!</title>
		<link>/10-cancer-causing-foods-you-should-stop-eating/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[adminilyes1]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 06 Jan 2021 12:09:52 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[wellness]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=673</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[This article is going to save you from the incoming cancer symptoms or disease in your life! Because these foods really cause cancers according to studies. Cancer! This word itself seems to be threatening and lethal. Cancer can hurt you physically, financially, mentally and psychologically. You must want to avoid this life hurting disease at [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>This article is going to save you from the incoming cancer symptoms or disease in your life! Because these foods really cause cancers according to studies.</p>



<p>Cancer! This word itself seems to be threatening and lethal. Cancer can hurt you physically, financially, mentally and psychologically. You must want to avoid this life hurting disease at your best.</p>



<p>But do you know? The worst offenders of this disease might be in your kitchen right now… And you probably be eating those foods in your daily routine and life.</p>



<p>Check the list below, click on the next button to move to the next one.</p>



<p>10. Grilled Red Meat<br>Grilled red meat causes cancer in humans</p>



<p>Grilled meat tastes delicious but it can cause cancer and excessive use of it also disturb the stomach.</p>



<p>When we prepare meat in this way, researchers say that it releases a carcinogen called heterocyclic aromatic amines. And it changes the molecule composition of meat.</p>



<p>Solution: Baking, broiling and cooking organically is the best alternative and safe side.</p>



<p>9. Canned Foods</p>



<p>Canned foods also cause cancer in humans, the latest researches told. The can in which canned foods are stored is lined with a chemical bisphenol-A (BPA). This is found to be alternating rat’s brain cells.</p>



<p>Solution: Save yourself by using fresh and organic vegetables and foods, or use frozen foods.</p>



<p>8. Microwave Popcorn<br>Microwave popcorn causes cancer in humans</p>



<p>Yum! Doesn’t it delicious? You might enjoy them on a daily basis while watching your TV or Netflix movies. But do you know it also causes cancer?</p>



<p>The flavoring agent used in Microwave popcorn releases diacetyl, a known toxin when cooked. And the popcorn bags are lined with perfluorooctanoic it itself is carcinogenic. It is considered as the center of lung cancer all over the world.</p>



<p>Solution: You should make your own organic popcorn in old fashioned-way on your stove or in proper air.</p>



<p>7. Soda</p>



<p>Soda is of no use to human health, and it has no positive effect on our health. But it has a lot of negative effects. It is loaded with a lot of sugar which is already enough for the problem. Filled with high-fructose corn syrup (HFCS), dyes, and a host of other chemicals, they are very bad for every aspect of your health.</p>



<p>Solution: Drink plain water or if you have craving for beverages choose from fresh fruit juices or choose from natural brands of soda without caramel color.</p>



<p>6. Hydrogenated Oils</p>



<p>Hydrogenated oils are not extracted from their sources naturally, but they undergo a chemical process to do so. And more chemicals are added to preserve them and making their consistency which leads to high levels of<br>omega-6 fats. You might have already heard about the risks of using hydrogenated oils.</p>



<p>Actually our body uses consumed fats and oils for the formation or repair of our cell membrane and consuming hydrogenated oils can totally change the structure of our body cells and this can lead to cancer.</p>



<p>Solution: Choose from olive, soy and other organic oils that are naturally extracted from their sources.</p>



<p>5. White Flour</p>



<p>White flour is also called refined flour, the process with which it is refined it produces new carcinogens in it. First of all, all nutrition value is removed from flour and then it is bleached with chlorine gas.</p>



<p>The glycemic index of white flour is very high, it can increase your insulin levels without providing you any nutrition. The carbohydrates are converted into sugars, and you already know how much dangerous sugar is for your health.</p>



<p>Solution: Choose organic and unbleached flour for your cooking and bread.</p>



<p>4. Alcohol</p>



<p>Studies have shown that alcohol can cause cancers of the head and neck, esophagus, liver, breast, and colon. People can safely drink one glass of alcohol per day but more than it is very dangerous to health.</p>



<p>Studies show that Alcohol actually ranks just behind tobacco as a substance highly correlated with the development of cancer.</p>



<p>Solution: Keep your alcohol consumption in a low-risk category and consume less.</p>



<p>3. Farmed Fish</p>



<p>Farmed fish is not as much healthier as wild-caught fish. Because farmed fishes are grown in large numbers and in a crowded environment and they are fed with an unhealthy diet, which contains different chemicals and steroids. Which fills very much bad stuff in their bodies. And to take control of bacteria and viral breakout they are treated with antibiotics and different pesticides. Farmed fish also don’t have as much omega-3 as wild salmon.</p>



<p>Solution: Eat wild-caught fish, try not to consume farmed fishes.</p>



<p>2. Refined Sugar (White Sugar)</p>



<p>This is the biggest cancer-causing food so far. As we know, cancer loves to feed on sugar. It literally feeds the cancer cells and helps them grow and spread. Who would want that?</p>



<p>It is high fructose corn syrup, and it is the source of major insulin spikes and feeds cancer cells in the body. You must avoid it as much as possible. You can find a ton of sugar in your daily diet, for example, a 20 oz soda has 15 teaspoons of sugar.</p>



<p>Solution: You must use organic honey as the best alternative, or you can use coconut sugar or maple sugar.</p>



<p>1. Artificial Sweeteners</p>



<p>Some people think that by switching to artificial sweeteners they can cut their danger of disease and can stay healthy, but they are absolutely wrong. Artificial sweeteners, particularly aspartame, are extremely dangerous and carcinogenic. Aspartame itself might be metabolized as the toxin DKP.</p>



<p>Solution: And organic plan based sweetener can help you if you really want to switch from sugars to sweeteners i.e Stevia. Or you can use honey or coconut sugar.</p>



<p>This was a list of top 10 Cancer causing foods that are eating in your daily life. You need to cut them off or need to decrease their use. Some of them are more dangerous and some are less, but the reality is, they are dangerous. Now, it’s up to you if you want to save yourself from cancer.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
