<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>LIFE &#8211; Dailytweet</title>
	<atom:link href="/category/life/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>/</link>
	<description></description>
	<lastBuildDate>Sat, 09 Jan 2021 14:43:43 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=5.6</generator>

<image>
	<url>/wp-content/uploads/2020/12/cropped-android-chrome-512x512-1-1-32x32.png</url>
	<title>LIFE &#8211; Dailytweet</title>
	<link>/</link>
	<width>32</width>
	<height>32</height>
</image> 
	<item>
		<title>WHAT ARE THE BEST WORKOUT ROUTINES FOR PEOPLE OVER 40</title>
		<link>/what-are-the-best-workout-routines-for-people-over-40/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[adminilyes1]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sat, 09 Jan 2021 14:35:03 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Inspire]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[LIFE]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=700</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[The workout is very vital in our lives, it helps our muscles to be healthy and strong. And it also keeps our body’s vital organs healthy and sharp. When you stop working out and do not exercise, you might be a victim of muscle weakness and stiffness. Which might be worse in the age above [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>The workout is very vital in our lives, it helps our muscles to be healthy and strong. And it also keeps our body’s vital organs healthy and sharp. When you stop working out and do not exercise, you might be a victim of muscle weakness and stiffness. Which might be worse in the age above 40. This article will cover the best workout routines for people over 40 years.</p>



<p>As we grow older our goals with the workout changes, and here today I am writing about 6 best workout routines which can help you to achieve your fitness goals. Whatever they are, you must choose your workout according to your reasons.</p>



<p>Let’s move to our main point without wasting any time and see what are the best workout routines for people over 40 years.</p>



<h2><strong>6</strong><strong>High-Intensity Interval Training</strong></h2>



<figure class="wp-block-image"><a href="https://web.archive.org/web/20200926180045/https://dailyvines.net/wp-content/uploads/2019/09/high-intensity-interval-training-workout-routine.jpg"><img src="https://web.archive.org/web/20200926180045im_/https://dailyvines.net/wp-content/uploads/2019/09/high-intensity-interval-training-workout-routine-696x435.jpg" alt=""/></a></figure>



<p>In short, if your goal is to burn extra body fat as efficiently as possible, then HIIT is the best option for you.</p>



<p>HIIT is short of High-Intensity Interval Training. HIIT is the small bursts of high-intensity exercises with shorter rests.</p>



<p>It increases your metabolic rate very significantly and also improves heart rate. This exercise routine has been very useful and effective in every age group. But as you hit the 40 years figure, it’s for sure that your body will have extra fat hanging around if you have been inactive for some time.</p>



<p>So, let me tell you the proper way of doing HIIT. You can literally do HIIT with any cardio equipment or any cardio exercise, you can also do two different exercises on alternate pauses.</p>



<p>For example, do the treadmill in high intensity&nbsp;<strong>i.e. 14 Kmph for 30 seconds</strong>&nbsp;or till you get out of stamina then do&nbsp;<strong>30 seconds on low intensity i.e. 6 Kmph.&nbsp;</strong>Repeat it 10-15 times and you are done. Same you can do with rope jumping, cycling or any other cardio. Best time to do HIIT is in the morning. This might be one of the best workout routines for people over 40.</p>



<p>Remember, This is the best workout routine for fat burning</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Eight Breathing Excercises You Can Try, When Feel Anxious</title>
		<link>/eight-breathing-excercises-you-can-try-when-feel-anxious/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[adminilyes1]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 08 Jan 2021 04:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[LIFE]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=697</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Anxietyis the state in which the Respiration or breathing got suppressed of seems to be arrested along with jerks due to flight and fright condition. When you feel so breathless, you can try multiple breathing techniques to diminish symptoms and feel better immediately. Let’s plan to do it now to build breathing sessions at any [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>Anxietyis the state in which the Respiration or breathing got suppressed of seems to be arrested along with jerks due to flight and fright condition. When you feel so breathless, you can try multiple breathing techniques to diminish symptoms and feel better immediately.</p>



<p>Let’s plan to do it now to build breathing sessions at any interval of time during the day at yourself.</p>



<h2>Lengthen your Exhale</h2>



<p>Deep inhaling is good but along with some more length in time, so it can calm you down immediately. Breathing is directly connected with the central nervous system and the specifically sympathetic part of it, which controls the flight- fright response. Alongside it, exhaling is governed by the parasympathetic part of the nervous system, which provides our body to relax and calm down.</p>



<p>Taking a natural breath is more than everything, but some due to anxiety state more respiration are required to normalize the flight-fright condition to save lives as well.</p>



<p>In such condition, short and more repeated breathings are seen, which is not a good thing to have, and deep breathing also hyperventilates the individuals, which slow the supply down the amount of oxygenated blood towards the brain. In stress or anxiety states we can end up the hyperventilates with more breathings.</p>



<ul><li>Let your lungs perform naturally and normally, but before breathing focus to a thorough and proper inhaling and exhaling by pushing the air completely to empty lungs and then take in lengthy and deep inhaling and repeat the phenomenon several.</li><li>Again you try to serve to breathe more time by inhaling and exhaling. If you inhale five seconds span then exhale improve to seven seconds span.</li><li>Repeat this exercise for five to ten minutes and become normal.</li></ul>



<p>This activity can be done variously at any position or posture comfortable for you by standing sitting or lying down.</p>



<h2>Abdomen on Breathing</h2>



<p>In order to breathe in from your diaphragm can improve the body’s capacity to do in order to breathe better.</p>



<p>Let we see how to breathe from the diaphragm</p>



<p><strong>Check-in</strong></p>



<ul><li>Sit relaxed on the chair a chair with knees bent or lie down on the floor or bed with a pillow beneath your head and knees comfortably.</li><li>Put your one hand over your heart and one hand under your rib cage.</li><li>Thoroughly inhale from the nose by keeping notice how your stomach and chest work together during breathing.</li><li>Isolate your breathing deeper into the lungs and then reverse.</li></ul>



<p><strong>Practice Belly Breathing</strong></p>



<ol><li>Conditioned yourself as above.</li><li>Put your one hand on your belly button and other on the chest.</li><li>Thoroughly breath from nose viewing your stomach rise but chest remains silent.</li><li>Exhale from the mouth by evolving your stomach muscles to push the air out.</li></ol>



<p>Practice doing this for ten minutes by using your diaphragm.</p>



<h2>Breath Focus</h2>



<p>At any comfortable location Sit or lie down and focus on breathing techniques.</p>



<ul><li>Feel your body to normal breathing.</li><li>Breath in slow and deep from the nose.</li><li>Feel your belly and upper body expanding.</li><li>Exhale in a comfortable manner.</li><li>Feeling your belly rise and down.</li><li>Focus by vocalizing a word of your choice like easy or relax.</li><li>Feel some relaxing move.</li><li>Think to boost your energy.</li><li>Keep complete attention toward exercise.</li></ul>



<p>Rehearse this for up to 10 minutes every day.</p>



<h2>Equal Breathing</h2>



<p>A yoga Aasan called pranayama is an exact exercise of equal breathing.</p>



<p>Positioned yourself in a sit or lying manner comfortably paying full attention.</p>



<ul><li>Pay extra attention and shut your eyes and take several normal breaths.</li><li>Count 1-2-3-4 and 5 by slow inhaling from the nose.</li><li>Exhale as the same as above. Feel lungs to be filled completely and emptying completely.</li></ul>



<p>Keep the inhale and exhale equal in time and counts. Your count can vary but keep concentrate.</p>



<h2>Resonant Breathing</h2>



<p>Coherent breathing or Resonant breathing can help you to calm anxiety and relax.</p>



<ul><li>Relaxed down and keep close your eyes.</li><li>Smoothly breath by the nose for 5 seconds</li><li>Don’t apply pressure to the lungs.</li><li>Exhale for five seconds the same as above with no force.</li><li>Continue it for 10 minutes</li><li>Keep more attentive during this spell to get maximum energy.</li></ul>



<p><strong>Yoga breathing&nbsp; (Pranayama)</strong></p>



<p>This yoga Aasan includes multiple breathings with variations which can help in anxiety to be lessens. Many of these comprising lengthened exhale, equal exhale, lion’s breath and alternate nostril breathing (Nadi shodhana).</p>



<h2>Lion’s Breath</h2>



<p>Exhaling with pressure is of a lion’s style of breathing.</p>



<ul><li>Sit in a cross-legged or position or kneeling with crossed ankles and resting bottom and breath.</li><li>Bring your hands to your knees, Stretch out your arms and fingers.</li><li>Inhale from the nose.</li><li>Exhale from mouth.</li><li>Relax your face during inhaling.</li><li>Again and again this practice up to ten times. Changing the cross of your ankles when you reach the half limit.</li></ul>



<h2>Alternate Nostril Breathing</h2>



<p>Sit at a straight spine and at a comfortable place and opening your chest wide. Reset your left hand in lap and raise the right hand. Rest the pointer and middle fingers of your right hand on forehead, in between the eyebrows. Close eye exhale and then inhale from the nose.</p>



<ul><li>With your right-hand close nostril and inhale slowly from left.</li><li>Hold breath block the nose with finger and thumb for a little while.</li><li>Inhale slowly from the right nostril.</li><li>Again block nose with finger and thumb and hold the breath for a little while.</li><li>Open the left side and exhale, wait for a moment before inhaling again.</li><li>Do this cycle again and again for 10 minutes. Remember each cycle would of 40-50 seconds.</li></ul>



<h2>Guided meditation</h2>



<p>Guided meditation is used to alleviate anxiety by interrupting patterns of thinking that perpetuate stress. A guided meditation by lying or sitting comfortably at dark and cello place and breathing and relaxing your brain and body muscles.</p>



<p>Listening of calming recordings help you gain control over intrusive thoughts that trigger anxiety. Meditation helps you improve new habits and thinking patterns.</p>



<p><strong>The takeaway</strong></p>



<p>At such a time the right approach is necessary to adopt, but few of the above-given techniques can be experienced if symptoms control your anxiety level and diffuse the stress otherwise have an appointment with your family doctor immediately to control the situation.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>7 Ways To Relieve Stress</title>
		<link>/seven-ways-to-relieve-stress/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[adminilyes1]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 08 Jan 2021 03:35:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[LIFE]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=694</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[When we feel stressed, we do things that we will end up regretting. Therefore, it would be best if you could get rid of it as soon as possible. You are going to be wasting a lot of time being stressed. You are going to think about negative things but it would be better to [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>When we feel stressed, we do things that we will end up regretting. Therefore, it would be best if you could get rid of it as soon as possible. You are going to be wasting a lot of time being stressed. You are going to think about negative things but it would be better to be positive all the time. Besides, life is short so there is no point in wasting time thinking of the wrong things. Here are some ways to relieve stress:</p>



<h2>1. Take a Vacation</h2>



<p>If you can, you can take leave from work. You can head to the nearest beach or another country that you may like. Better read some blog posts about the country so you can see if you will like the activities there. You can do a ton of activities depending on where you go. It would be better to set an itinerary before going so you will know what you are going to do. When you meet some amazing people, you can expect your plans to eventually change. It is perfectly alright as the most important thing is you have a lot of fun. Why would you want to do something that you are not fond of? For example, if you get invited to diving and you are not fond of being underwater then don’t go with them.</p>



<h2>2. Laugh</h2>



<p>There are many ways to make you laugh. You can watch a comedy movie, attend a standup show, or even tickle yourself. You will forget about all your problems when you laugh and you will shift to thinking about happy thoughts. It would also be great to hang out with people who make you laugh all the time. You don’t even have to pay them and they would love to tell funny stories while time passes by. You will notice these are the types of people who have a lot of friends so they will rarely make time for you. However, when you are with them, it will be all worth it as you will enjoy yourself a lot.</p>



<h2>3. Exercise</h2>



<p>You are going to be hitting two birds with one stone when you exercise. Not only will you lose a bunch of calories but you will also be relieving stress. After all, you are going to be stressed when you see in the mirror that you are pretty out of shape. It all starts with exercising then it continues with eating the right food.</p>



<p>After all, exercising will be pretty useless when you always eat the wrong food. Also, there are many forms of exercise that you can do and some of them are quite fun. How about hitting the gym and doing a group exercise with fellow fitness freaks? You can dance to the beat of your favorite artists while losing weight in the process. You can also play sports with friends and you won’t keep track of the number of calories that you have lost.</p>



<h2>4. Take a Yoga Class</h2>



<p>Yoga is pretty popular because of how it relieves stress. There are a variety of classes that you can attend and they are all great. You would need to have a yoga mat though but most yoga studios already provide mats.</p>



<h2>5. Take Supplements</h2>



<p>There are a lot of supplements that take with stress so better ask the staff what the best ones are. After that, check out the ingredients and see if your body is not allergic to any of it.</p>



<h2>6. Go Out with Friends</h2>



<p>There are people who just send you a text message when they need something. It would be time to get rid of those types of people in your life. It would be better to go out with friends who understand you for who you are. All of you should have a common interest. For example, going out for dinner maybe your thing but dancing at the nearest club is not. Of course, you must remember to not go out too late at night. You may get into an accident. It would be great if you have some true friends. As life goes on, you are going to meet a lot of people.</p>



<p>All these things can be done with minimal effort. For example, you won’t even need to spend much on exercise. Instead of getting a membership at the nearest gym, you can just jog with your friends at the nearest park. That will save you a lot of money because you won’t need to spend a single cent doing that. There are also some YouTube videos you can watch that will guide you on the many exercises you can do for that day. It depends on what you want to do.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>WHAT ARE THE EFFECTS OF CAFFEINE ON HUMAN BODY?</title>
		<link>/what-are-the-effects-of-caffeine-on-human-body/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[adminilyes1]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 06 Jan 2021 13:02:39 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[LIFE]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=685</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Caffeine can make you very energetic and active. But this effect may not last very long if you keep overdosing your daily caffeine intake. Let’s see what are the effects of Caffeine on Human body, even they are good or bad. You know that everything has some good and some bad effects. And you might [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>Caffeine can make you very energetic and active. But this effect may not last very long if you keep overdosing your daily caffeine intake. Let’s see what are the effects of Caffeine on Human body, even they are good or bad.</p>



<p>You know that everything has some good and some bad effects. And you might also have heard the quote: “Excess of everything is bad”. So, without any further delay lets see what effects caffeine can have on our body, good or bad.</p>



<p>What is Caffeine?<br>According to Wikipedia, Caffeine is a central nervous system stimulant of the methylxanthine class.</p>



<p>It is a chemical found in tea, coffee, carbonated drinks, and some energy drinks.</p>



<p>What Amount of Caffeine is Too Much?<br>On average Americans drink up to 3 cups of coffee per day. Which contains 100mg of caffeine.</p>



<p>There exists a LETHAL dose of caffeine, which is 10g. But an average cup of coffee contains only 100mg to 200mg of caffeine. It means you need to consume at least 50 to 100 cups of coffee a day to reach the max limit of caffeine which will be lethal for you.</p>



<p>So, it is almost impossible to overdose caffeine to a lethal level with a normal routine.</p>



<p>But, there is an overdose that can make you feel no good and can affect our body in negative ways. FDA only recommends 4 to 5 cups of coffee, for a healthy adult, in a day.</p>



<p>Also read: Breast Cancer 101: Symptoms, Types, and Causes of Breast Cancer</p>



<p>Effects of Caffeine on Human Body<br>I hope you now you are very clear about the dosage of caffeine. Now I am going to discuss some positive and negative effects which caffeine can have on our body.</p>



<p>Keeps Focused and Energetic<br>When you drink a cup of coffee, the caffeine present in it the adrenal glands and they release adrenaline hormone to our system. Which tells our brain to stay energetic and focused.</p>



<p>More Leads to Less Focus<br>But when we consume it too much it makes you less focused and sluggish at bedtimes. Studies tell.</p>



<p>Enhances Memory<br>Some researches show that an amount of caffeine enhances memory. But most researches have shown the mixed results, some say it does not affect our memory.</p>



<p>In research by John Hopkins University, they have found that the intake of caffeine enhances long-term memory after a learning session.</p>



<p>You would like to read: Benefits of Giving up Alcohol</p>



<p>Alertness<br>It stimulates our central nervous system, after intaking of caffeine you feel more alert, less tired and more active. You can also focus well as I have stated in the first point. It is a common ingredient to treat drowsiness and headaches.</p>



<p>Speeds Up Metabolism, Enhances Weight Loss<br>Caffeine can promote weight loss in both men and women by increasing body metabolism.</p>



<p>Caffeine suppresses the appetite and reduces the desire to eat more. And it also promotes the thermogenesis, which means it makes our body to generate more heat and energy from digested food.</p>



<p>Taking a cup of black coffee before a workout or weight loss exercises can make your weight loss journey faster.</p>



<p>Lessens the Risk of Alzheimer’s and Dementia<br>According to Healthline, people who drink coffee regularly tend to possess less risk of developing Alzheimer’s and Dementia.</p>



<p>More Leads to Day Fatigues<br>When you consume more coffee, and most usually consume it at nights before bedtimes. Then it can develop fatigues in your coming routine.</p>



<p>This happens because when you take excess caffeine or near to bedtimes, then it becomes hard to sleep at night and deep sleep. So the next day when you wake up you feel tired because you didn’t manage to get enough deep sleep. And on the next day, you again take caffeine to make your day active and energetic.</p>



<p>Prevents Cancer<br>Some resources and studies clearly suggested that people who drink coffee or take caffeine have a lower risk of developing different types of cancers, like skin cancer, oral cancer, prostate cancer, and Breast cancer.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>7 TIPS TO QUIT SMOKING AT YOUR OWN</title>
		<link>/7-tips-to-quit-smoking-at-your-own/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[adminilyes1]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 06 Jan 2021 12:56:52 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[LIFE]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=682</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Are you a smoker and tired of your smoking life? Do you want to quit smoking? If you have a “Yes” to all these questions then you are in the right place. Here I will be sharing some tips to quit smoking. In the exact next 5 minutes, I am going to show you the [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>Are you a smoker and tired of your smoking life? Do you want to quit smoking? If you have a “Yes” to all these questions then you are in the right place. Here I will be sharing some tips to quit smoking.</p>



<p>In the exact next 5 minutes, I am going to show you the right ways to quit smoking on your own…</p>



<p>You will surely be able to quit smoking if you will follow these instructions with sincerity and regularity…</p>



<p>Promise? Okay!</p>



<p>Stay with me and we can kick this lethal and life hurting habit very quickly…</p>



<p>As you might know, there are different ways in which you can quit smoking. The best plan is one you can stick with.</p>



<p>Before start reading further ask your self some questions and write down the answers on page:</p>



<p>Is smoking addiction stronger than me? Is smoking more important to me than my life? How would be my life if I was a non-smoker? Wouldn’t I be happier without cigarette smoking?</p>



<p>Before taking your first step towards quitting smoking. You must know its after effects and possible threats. I have some resources for you. <a rel="noreferrer noopener" target="_blank" href="http://nhs.uk/">nhs.uk</a> have a detailed report of how its affects our body.</p>



<p>And MedicalNewsToday also discussed bad effects of smoking on our body.</p>



<p>You would like to read: Warning Signs and Symptoms of Heart Attack</p>



<p>Let’s discuss how can we quit or stop smoking with simple tips and habits.</p>



<p>1. Why did you start smoking?<br>First of all, before taking your first step towards quit-smoking therapy, you need to find the reason why you have started smoking and when? And when you find or remember that reason, you need to check if that problem or condition still persists with you or not.</p>



<p>If that problem or condition is still with you then you need to cut it off, try your best to solve your problem or put yourself out from that condition. Try to forget it… Because if you will still have that problem in your life then you might remember on some point and your left smoking habit might again trigger.</p>



<p>So this is your first step towards quit-smoking…</p>



<p>2. Find a reason to Quit Smoking<br>You must have a strong reason to quit your smoking habit because it will help you stay motivated all the time whenever you will think to smoke again.</p>



<p>The reason might be to save your family or near ones from secondhand smoking (passive smoking) or save yourself from lung cancer, mouth cancer or heart diseases.</p>



<p>If you have tried to quit smoking before and failed, don’t let that be an obstacle.</p>



<p>Choose a reason that is strong enough to outweigh the urge to light up…</p>



<p>3. Tell your near ones<br>Tell everyone who is near to you and your loved ones that you want to quit smoking and taking measures to quit smoking. Ask for their support, it will help you a lot. Quitting is easier with support.</p>



<p>Ask them to stop you every time whenever you think of smoking or try to light up the cigarette again. They will listen to you and will distract you.</p>



<p>This will help a lot…</p>



<p>4. Oral supply replacement<br>Once you are addicted to cigarette, your mouth is also addicted to being busy with it all the time. In easy words, you also attain oral addiction.</p>



<p>So, when you will not smoke for some time, your mouth will crave for something to have in it. You might fill this craving with chewing gum, appetizers, nuts, carrots, raw vegetables, etc. Anything you would like to chew.</p>



<p>5. Remove all reminders<br>You must keep your environment smoking free, you should remove all smoking remainders you might have in your bedroom, home, office or car. Like, ashtray, cigarette buds, smoke, smoking posters, lighters, and matches, etc.</p>



<p>Cigarette smoke is also a trigger to smoking, so also avoid it as much as possible. This will be of great help…</p>



<p>6. Quit Slowly don’t panic<br>As you know, success always comes slowly! So, this sentence applies to everything as long as we are on this planet. You need to remember this every time you leave a cigarette or throw it.</p>



<p>Quit smoking one day at a time. It will be easier for you, once you start quitting. Quit one at a time then try to add up days and then follow the same strategy. Don’t try to quit at once, because it could be overwhelming.</p>



<p>Always remember, smoking is never been powerful than you! You can do it!</p>



<p>7. Maintenance and Stress management<br>Maintenance:<br>Because you have been a cigarette addict, that’s why you would have the cravings in intervals. But you must think at that point that how strong you have been in quitting.</p>



<p>Remember your reasons to quit. And don’t let your addiction to overcome you, because it is not stronger than you and will never be.</p>



<p>Start to see yourself as a non-smoker. That is the ultimate payoff. You are freeing yourself from the control of your addiction.</p>



<p>Stress Management:<br>Eat healthy food like vegetables, fruits, and dry fruits. Get a lot of rest on your times. You might your self have noted that stress is a key trigger to smoking. You have to cut off your stress and conditions in which you get stressed.</p>



<p>You can use substitutes for oral cravings as I already described it in the above section. Whenever you feel down, take deep breaths and calm down yourself, and believe in your self.</p>



<p>Bonus Tip!<br>Don’t let yourself get down if you have failed one time in quitting smoking then try again next week, never stop trying. In the end, it will be a success!</p>



<p>Always remember your reasons to quit smoking, researchers say that quitting is mostly a mind situation if you are successful in setting your mind on quitting and made it strong enough then you will surely do it.</p>



<p>And at the end, remember those answers to the questions which I asked to you at the start of this article </p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>5 AMAZING SECRETS OF SUCCESS IN LIFE</title>
		<link>/5-amazing-secrets-of-success-in-life/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[adminilyes1]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 06 Jan 2021 12:05:36 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[LIFE]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=669</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[This is not the issue in Life that you are Male or Female, You are a youngster or a matured one. It makes no difference at all, but if you implement these 5 secrets of success in your life then there is no goal or mission which would not be achieved by you. An Indian [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>This is not the issue in Life that you are Male or Female, You are a youngster or a matured one.</p>



<p>It makes no difference at all, but if you implement these 5 secrets of success in your life then there is no goal or mission which would not be achieved by you.</p>



<p>An Indian Philosopher famed as Sant Kabir gifted 5 secrets of success in life to the people as under.</p>



<p>The secret of success No. 1<br>To Know Meaning and Purpose of Life</p>



<p>Couplets of Sant Kabir.<br>Aya tha kis kam se, Tu soya Chadar taaan</p>



<p>(You came for what purpose, you slept covered with cloth sheet)</p>



<p>Surat Sambhal E Gafil, Apna aap Pehchan</p>



<p>(Hold a forgotten , identify yourself)</p>



<p>Translation and Commentary.</p>



<p>It Elaborates that for what purpose you came in life and for what purpose you born? i.e. what is your purpose to live a purposeful life among the 600 crore people, certainly would be there some purpose and meaning of your life to live. First thirty years of our life passed in wait and think that if I got some degree would be successful, or if I got some job so would be successful, or if got a life partner so would be successful. The remaining thirties passes to think and hope that would I have some job or would I have got some other offer or would I have joined some course. The philosopher says that until and unless you don’t know the meaning and purpose of your life, you won’t explore your dreams to success. All of it is most important to know about the purpose of life for which you came. We make our life so complicated and starts to ask big philosophical questions about, that what is the meaning of life and what is the purpose of life, somebody has said very well. The meaning of life is to live meaningfully and purpose of life is to live purposefully. You are required to know for what purpose you to live.</p>



<p>Work hard, party harder become such a culture in which, nobody is ready to think and ask that in which direction I am going. Is it the same and right direction in which I am going, for which my real inner self and soul wishes to. Nobody is ready to think over it, we all are running aimlessly. The Sant says that rise and wake up and know that for what goal you came in life. All of any work in you must be known to you that what is the purpose for me to come. Somebody said a well that a man who does not have a purpose worth enough to die for, does not deserve to live, i.e who don’t have a purpose for which he can die for to work hard. He has no right to live for. It is to say that you are to know to live for purpose and direction. It would be discussed separately how to know about your direction and goal at another time.</p>



<p>Conclusion: Meaning of life is to live meaningfully and Purpose of life is to live Purposefully.</p>



<p>The secret of success No. 2<br>Find your core Strength</p>



<p>Couplets of Sant Kabir.<br>Jahan na Jaake Gun Lahe, Tahan na taako Tham</p>



<p>( where your talent no demand, there you should not stay or live )</p>



<p>Dhobi bas ke kya kare, Digambar ke Gaam</p>



<p>( At the place the dry cleaner not tostay, where people are naked lived)</p>



<p>Translation and Commentary.</p>



<p>Elaborates that the place where your talent and skills acknowledge evaluated so you are no required to stay over there because your talent and skills would not be appreciated there, where such people are not living who needs. In such locality where people do not wear the clothes and live naked without clothes if you establish a dry clean shop there so that is useless for them who don’t wear the clothes and live like Digambar means, naked people. So you have to go there where your skills are required and demanded. You rush there where your natural talent is in great demand, and if it is not there so you are like those where people do not a wearer of clothes. If you are frustrated and too stressful, anxious in your present situation then probably it’s time to THINK. Find a conducive place for your Talent and skills to be Fruitful.</p>



<p>Conclusion: Everybody seems to be a misfit in their carrier and future. Find your core strength</p>



<p>The secret of success No. 3<br>THINK AND ATTEMPT BIG</p>



<p>Couplets of Sant Kabir.<br>Nadiya, Daata Ek sam – Jo aave, so Det</p>



<p>(Nadi and Daata are same – who come so gets)</p>



<p>Hast Khumb Jiska Jisa – Utna hi bhar let</p>



<p>(Gets as much as its capacity – you take per capacity)</p>



<p>Translation and Commentary.</p>



<p>Elaborates that the water stream flowing and the Lord are of same in giving you, Water stream execute the thirst of thirsty and Lord is giving to everybody to fulfills of hopes of theirs, who come, but in getting it is different because everybody has different capacity forgetting. The person who came for big to get he should take as much as per his desire and capacity if it is high or low another way. Means that Your vision should be big and broad. Think Big and Dreams big. If your vision and desire are to top the certainly you should do and if you think small then you are failed.</p>



<p>Conclusion: As big you think you would get the big results in your life. So your life would be great.</p>



<p>The secret of success No. 4<br>Seek and you shall find it</p>



<p>Couplets of Sant Kabir.<br>Jin Dhunda Tin Paaya – Gehare Paani Painth</p>



<p>( who seek they find – in deeper water )</p>



<p>Jo boura Duban Dara – Raha Kinare Baith</p>



<p>(who reluctant to sunk – sat at sore)</p>



<p>Translation and Commentary.</p>



<p>Who sought and find in the deep water, and who feared to sink so remained to sit at sore remained deprived. We must know that the pearls are always in deeper waters, pearls are not at the sores. You must to dive in deeper to get it. Your dreams are not be concluded by sitting at the sores you must dive in deeper sea. It is impossible at sores. You should take the risk. In a Chinese restaurant a waiter wearing a T-shirt written on it that A biggest risk in life is not to take the risk. Fear of failure is a great risk. The risk of sinking and risk of not leave sore is not likely to give you excellence in your life. If you will not overcome the fear of failure you won’t get the success. Conquering the Fear of Failure is the first step towards Success. Remember that where the probability of excellence is there the fear of sinking is there. So seek in deeper sea and fulfill your dreams.</p>



<p>The secret of success No. 5<br>Work Hard, Perseverance is the Key</p>



<p>Couplets of Sant Kabir.<br>Sharam se Sabkuch Hot hai – Man Jo Raakhe Dheer</p>



<p>(Hard work makes everything – if heart retains patience)</p>



<p>Sharam se khodat koop Jyun – Thal mai Prakate neer</p>



<p>(As well is dig with hard work – in desert water explored)</p>



<p>Translation and Commentary.</p>



<p>Without hard work nothing can be done. The people don’t know the real sense of hard-working. Nobody knows the definition of hard work. People presume to which real hard work is not hard work. Perseverance is the key to success. In those circumstances when everything seems impossible, the muscled people do the dumbbells, and the people like this go forward and this is the real hard-working otherwise is the wishful thinking. Today it is a big problem that we are ready to do ten things but not ready to complete one thing for 10 months. Sant Kabir says that you should be perseverance with hard work, be patience be. I know some of the people who are trying to lose weight. Everybody is trying to lose weight fast. If you search in google and type how to lose 40 kg weight the auto-suggestion # 1 will be that in one month, can you imagine, which is not possible even you lay on rail track? But people try to lose 40 kg in one month. This is the desire and efforts. They do 10 things for only one month but not do one thing for 10 months.</p>



<p>Conclusions: Consequently understand your direction, find your purpose, your field, Think and Attempt Big, Take Risk, Take Action, Work Hardest and achieve the Goal.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
